SACHINI DISSANAYAKA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

sachini-dissanayaka_github.io ◆ github.com/sachini-dissanayaka ◆ linkedin.com/in/sachini-dissanayaka

Reading, London, United Kingdom ♦ sachinidissanayaka269@gmail.com ♦ (+44) 79 35 099111

EDUCATION

BSc Engineering (Hons) Sp. in Computer Science and Engineering

University of Moratuwa - Sri Lanka

2018 - 2022

- Graduated with a Second class upper division (Overall GPA 3.62 out of 4.20)
- · Selected in to the Dean's List on 3 semesters
- Served as an executive committee member and a lead organiser in the UoM Leo Club, UoM IEEE, and MoraSpirit Club
- Selected as the batch representative in the university final year
- Secured multiple hackathon wins during the undergraduate period

GCE Advanced Level Examination

Anamaduwa Central College - Sri Lanka

2008 - 2016

- Scored distinction passes with 3A's for the all 3 subjects (Combined Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry). Ranked the 1st in the district with a Z-score of 2.3770
- Served in the Senior and Junior Prefect boards from 2010 to 2016

ACHIEVEMENTS

IEEE Xtreme

 Ranked 18th and 57th in the country respectively in the years of 2021 and 2019 in the IEEE Xtreme competitive programming competition

IEEE YESIST 12

 Ranked 4th in the Preliminary Selection Competition within the country in 2019 and got selected for the finals in Stamford University in Thailand

HackDown

• Selected to the finalists by being the 19th of the country in HackDown coding competition in 2020

PUBLICATIONS

 Two-Factor Authentication with TOTP using Speakeasy

Article Link

Article Link

Integration of Huawei Account Kit

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Leo Club, University of Moratuwa

- Served as the chairman of "Mini-Miracles" project in the year 2019
- Served as a member of the IT panel from 2020 to 2021

MoraSpirit, University of Moratuwa

 Served as a volunteer article writer the years from 2019 to 2021

PROFILE

I'm a passionate programmer who has around 2 years of experience in developing software. My interests lies with System Design, Software Security, NLP, Competitive Programming, and Data Science. I have worked with Java, Python, React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, and GCP. Currently, I'm looking for a great team to find my next adventure as a Software Engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

WSO2 Inc - Java, Maven

May 2022 - Jan 2023

- WSO2 is an open source technology provider in the API Management domain
- I worked on the version migration of the Twilio SDK from 3.3.13 to 8.36.0 in Twilio ESB Connector. This was an urgent customer end request which I completed within minimum time
- I contributed to the integration test management, APIM support and APIM regression test handling and improvement

Software Engineer - Intern

Emojot (Pvt) Ltd - React, Node.js, MongoDB

Oct 2020 - May 2021

- Emojot is a global pioneer in real-time emotion-based intelligent experience management
- Contributed to the system security enhancement by implementing a multi-factor authentication system for Emojot Dashboard and Customer Experience Management Portal (CX Portal)
- CX Portal is the main client-facing application of the Emojot platform and the authentication improvements were critical in securing user accounts
- Improved the user operations management and setup user authorisation levels to monitor user engagement

PROJECTS & RESEARCHES

Research - Hybrid-Attention End-to-End Speaker Diarization Model

Deep Learning, PyTorch, Python, GCP

- This was based on the implementation of the state-of-the-art model for 2 speaker overlapping speech diarization by reducing the Diarization Error Rate (DER)
- We proposed three more models by improving the current state-of-the-art Self Attention model, which are combinations of Local Dense Synthesizer-Attention layer with Self Attention, Relative Attention and External Attention layers

Simplified Search Engine - Sinhala Language

Source Code

Python, Flask, React.js, BeautifulSoup, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Firebase

- This is an information retrieval system that can be used to query and get any type of data about Sinhala Politicians
- The dataset of the project was scrapped using BeautifulSoup and the project was implemented using Python, React.js, and supported by a python-Flask powered backend

Distributed Chat System

Source Code

Java, Maven, JUnit

- The chat system consists of two main parties namely the clients and servers
- The system supports multiple servers at a moment, and leader election algorithm was used to automatically self-assign a particular server instance as the leader
- Heartbeat algorithm using gossiping and consensus was used for failure detection across the system
- Clients has the ability connect across different servers and manage their own communication sessions similar to chat rooms

Kritify

Source Code

Java, Android Studio, SpringBoot

- This a social medai mobile app that hosts reviews about business entities in one place.
- The android app was developed by integrating with HMS core and Huawei Account Kit and Huawei Map Kit